DAN KLEIN: So the last thing for today
is we're going to see the effect of
this in the demo.
Here is our big graph.
Let's say we're doing just
forward checking.
This graph is too easy already if
we're doing arc consistency.
When we do no ordering, what happens?
Well, we assign the first
four variables and
suddenly we have a problem.
Arc consistency detects this,
forward checking does not.
With forward checking, we now have to
kind of mess around with all these
other variables first before
we discover our mistake.
What if we stick with forward checking,
but we switch so that now
we're doing ordering with minimum
remaining values?
Well, we'll still assign
blue in the lower left.
Then we'll still assign red.
Except now we see that this variable
appears very constrained.
Rather than just marching to the
right, we should probably go do
something about it.
And so we're going to assign it next.
So we'll go and assign up there.
Now we see this variable down here that
used to be kind of the other half
of the tricky configuration, it's
now the constrained variable.
So we might go down there
now and then continue.
And we kind of follow the consequences
of our assignments along the graph.
So even though this is just forward
checking, we're able to do much
better, straight through.
So all of these ideas are important.
And on small problem instances, it's
actually hard to show all of them
being necessary.
But when you have all of these things,
you have ordering, you have filtering,
and next time we'll see structure, you
can often speed up things greatly in a
general case.
I think we're done for today.
Next time, we'll pick up with other
methods for speeding up CSPs.